

Contacts

- **** +37256193750
- ☐ aliglbayatpour@gmail.com
- alibayatpour.com
- in linkedin.com/in/ali-bayatpourb0179912a/
- stackoverflow.com/users/12576676/ali-
- ☐ Tööstuse 83, 10416, Tallinn, Estonia

Skills



Profile

Hi, I'm Ali, a software engineer based in Tallinn. I've been in the software academic and working environment for **9 years**. I studied Computer Science as my bachelor's and MBA with a focus on Software Project management as my master's while working as a software engineer. It's been almost four years that I've been working as a web developer in different roles, including Freelance web developer, Front-end, Full-stack, and Software development team lead.

Work Experience

Single.Earth

lyr llmos

Software Development Team Lead

Dec 2021 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Writing Go on the backend and Angular on the Front-end side.
- Following best practices and clean code architecture
- Writing unit and integration tests with Jest, Jasmine and Karma.
- Working closely with product managers to convert business tasks to technical tasks for the team
- Support the engineering team with code reviews, pair programming, and practical workshops.

Front-end Developer

Sep 2020 - Aug 2021

Responsibilities:

- Writing React(TypeScript) and Angular on the Front-end side.
- State management tools Redux for React and Rxjs for Angular
- Working closely with designers
- Writing clean code and high-performant code.
- Build SEO-friendly apps
- Being able to work with Next.js and Angular Universal for supporting server-side rendering.

NatureHub

4 mos

Frontend Web Developer

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

Responsibilities:

- Building Web Apps with Angular
- Building Mobile Apps with Ionic + Angular
- Building fast SEO-friendly products
- Working closely with designers
- Focus on the improving UI and UX

Self-employed

1 yr 5 mos

Freelance Web Development

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

Responsibilities:

- Building Web Apps with React + TypeScript
- Building SEO-friendly and beautiful web apps for different industries including: Digital Agencies, Real Estate, Restaurants(Online Food Order), Digital Market and many more.
- Building browser based games with complex animations

Education

Tallinn University of Technology

Master's degree, MBA (Software Project Management)

2019 - Jan 2022

• Thesis Topic: Usefulness of the Scrum, A Study Among Startups.

Persian Gulf University

◆ Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering

2014 - 2018

- Academic projects with Java, C, VHDL, C#
- Professor Assistant in Data Structures